[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我需要演示这是如何工作的，因为我可以
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I need to demonstrate how this works because I can
整天谈论一个函数并返回一个函数。
talk all day about a function and returns a function.
但如果我们不把它弄乱，那就没有任何意义了。
But if we don't actually mess with it, it won't make any sense.
所以，让我从一个非常简单的例子开始。
So, let me start with a very simple example.
我们将创建一个名为digit_name的函数，
We're gonna make a function called digit_name,
digit_name将接受一个字符串或接受一个数字并返回一个字符串。
digit_name will take a string or take a number and return a string.
根据这个数字。
Based on what that number is.
它将通过返回字符串数组中的元素来实现这一点。
And it will do that by returning an element from an array of strings.
所以你可以看到这是非常微不足道的
So you can see this is very trivial and
不幸的是，我写这篇文章的方式有问题。
unfortunately there's a problem with the way I wrote this.
也就是说，我使用了一个名为names的全局变量。
And that is I'm using a global variable called names.
问题是如果在我的
The problem with that is If there is anything else in my
系统也有一个名为Names的全局变量。
system that also has a global variable called names.
我们会发生冲突，要么我的功能失败，要么
We're gonna get a conflict and either my functional fail or
他们的会失败，或者我们两个都会失败，这很糟糕。
theirs will fail or maybe we both fail and that's bad.
你没有办法进行测试，因为你不能预测
And there is no way you can test for that because you can't anticipate
你的代码必须运行的所有代码。
all of the code that your code is ever gonna have to run with.
如果你必须运行广告，这在浏览器中尤其是一个问题，
And this is especially a problem in browsers if you have to run with ads,
因为广告中有一些你见过的最糟糕的代码，
because ads come with some of the worst code you've ever seen,
因为他们会付钱让你收他们的垃圾，对吧？
because they'll pay you to take their crap, right?
你可以威胁他们说，我们不会接受你的广告，除非你清理
And you can threaten them and say, we're not gonna take your ads unless you clean
起来，他们会说，好的，我们会把钱给别人。
it up, and they'll say, okay, we'll get our money to someone else.
你说，好吧，只是开玩笑，它是如何工作的
And you say, all right, just kidding, how it works and
他们使用了很多全局变量，最终你会接到电话。
they use lots of global variables and eventually your gonna get the call.
你的东西因为一些广告不起作用了，但是
Your stuff stopped working because of some ad but
不是广告的错是你的错。
it's not the ads fault it's your fault.
所以我们需要减少对全局变量的依赖。
So we need to reduce our dependence on global variables.
所以这里有另一种方法，我可以写这个函数。
So here is another way that I could write this function.
这里我得到了digit name函数，它有一个名为names的私有变量，
Here I've got the digit name function and it has a private variable called names,
因为所有变量在函数范围内都是私有的。
because all variables are private within the function scope.
因此，如果存在名为Names的全局变量，则不会发生冲突，所以
So if there is a global variable called names, no conflict, so
真的很好。
that's all really good.
糟糕的是，每次我调用数字名称时，我都必须构造
The bad part is that every time I call digit name, I'm going to have to construct
一个新的数组，在里面放十个东西，这样我就可以从里面取出一个东西。
a new array, put ten things in it just so I can take one thing out of it.
太贵了。
That's hugely expensive.
现在优化编译器可以观察到名称作为指示的不变性，
Now an optimizing compiler might observe that names as invariant over indications,
因此它可能会尝试将其优化出来。
and so it might try to optimize that out.
但是优化编译器可能需要花费很多分钟来完成他们的工作，并且
But optimizing compilers can take many minutes to do their work, and
在网络上，我们不能花太多时间。
on the web we can't take many minutes.
我们必须立即开始，所以编译器总是非常快。
We have to start instantly, so the compilers are always gonna be really fast.
快速编译，所以他们不会这样做，所以我们需要这样做。
Get going quick compilers, so they're not gonna do this so we need to do this.
所以这里有第三种方法来编写这个函数。
So here's a third way to write this function.
这里，我有数字名，我有一个带有私有变量的函数
Here, I've got digit name, I've got a function with the private variable
包含名称，但这一次我返回的是一个函数。
containing the names, but this time I'm returning a function.
我返回的函数将使用这个名称。
And the function I return is going to use the name.
我马上调用外部函数，这意味着我要
And I'm calling the outer function immediately, which means that what I'm
将要存储在digit_name中的不是外部函数，而是
going to be storing in the digit_name is not the outer function, but
外部函数的返回值，恰好是内部函数。
the return value of the outer function, which happens to be the inner function.
以及内部功能，
And that inner function,
由于关闭，将继续访问Names变量。
because of closure, will continue to have access to the names variable.
即使在Green函数返回之后。
Even after the green function has returned.
这是我们这三天要讨论的最重要的想法，所以
This is the most important idea we're gonna talk about over these three days so
我想看到每个人，包括你在家里点头，就像是，好的，我明白了。
I want to see everybody including you at home nodding, like yeah, okay, I got that.
好的，你没拿到，所以我们再来一次。
Okay, you didn't get it, so let's do it again.
所以让我们重新开始。
So let's start over.
这是原来的好吗？
This is the original one, okay?
我们得到了全局变量。
We've got the global variable.
我们已经有了简单的数字名称函数。
We've got our our simple digit name function.
现在请记住我们刚才与租户和
Now remember the thing we just talked about with tenant and
他的对应原则，我们可以取任何值。
his correspondence principle that we can take any value.
将其包装在将返回该值的函数中，调用该函数
Wrap it in a function that will return that value, call that function
立即，这是同样的事情，所以在这种情况下，我可以这样做。
immediately and it's the same thing, so I can do that in this case.
我将把结果赋值给digit_name
I'm gonna assign to a digit_name the result
这个函数将返回我立即调用的函数。
of a function which will return a function that I call immediately.
所以你可以看到这个和这个做的是完全相同的事情。
So you can see that this and this do exactly the same thing.
这个只是更多的代码，好吗？
This one's just a little bit more code, okay?
那么每个人都对此感到满意吗？&gt；&gt；演讲者2：你能展示一下这两个吗？
So everybody comfortable with that? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Could you show those two?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, so
我们必须给变量赋值。
we're got to assign a value to the variable.
我们将分配调用一个函数的结果，该函数将返回
We're going to assign the result of calling a function that will return that
值立即调用函数。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：因此在本例中，
value in calling the function immediately. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So in this in this example,
是使用这个的主要好处，我们正在防止污染全球
is the main benefit of using this that we're preventing polluting the global
Stack，或者好处是什么？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：嗯，
stack, or what are the benefits? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Well,
这就是我们要去做的，我们还没有这样做。
that's what we'll get to, we haven't done that yet.
所以这两个人做的是完全相同的事情。
So these two are doing exactly the same thing.
让我们来讨论全局变量问题。
So let's go have the global variable problem.
我们还没修好任何东西。
We haven't fixed anything yet.
正在设置。现在你很熟悉我们的想法
Getting setup. Now you're familiar with the idea that we
可以有局部变量，
can have local variables,
在函数中声明一个变量，该变量是函数的局部变量。
declare a variable within a function that's local to the function.
我们有全局变量，所有函数都可以看到。
And we've got global variables which all the functions can see.
但我们可以拥有，所以这是两个世界，对吧，
But we can have, so that's two worlds, right,
你可以把它想象成实例世界和静态世界。
you can think of it as like the instance world and the static world.
不完全是那样的，但有点像那样，
It's not exactly like that but it's kinda like that,
我们有两个能见度。
we've got two levels of visibility.
但是我们可以做得更好，因为每次我们嵌套一个函数，我们都会得到一个新的
But we can go much finer because every time we nest a function, we get a new
我们可以存放东西的地方，另一个可以获取变量的地方。
place where we can keep stuff, another place where you can get variables.
并且每个函数都将确定可见性和
And each function will determine the visibility and
在其中定义的变量的生存期。
the lifetime of the variables that are defined inside of it.
因此，我们现在可以拥有的不仅仅是本地和全球
And so, it's not just local and global we can now have
在范围之间，它们只是范围。
in between scopes and and they're just scopes.
所以我要对这个做一个改变。
So I'm gonna make one change to this one.
我要取这个全局变量
I'm gonna take this global variable and
我只是将它向下移动一行，进入外部函数中，好吗？
I'm going to just move it down one line to be inside of the outer function, okay?
所以我们引入了第三个地方，我们可以保存东西，现在
So we've introduced a third place where we can keep stuff which is now
在外部函数的范围内。
in the scope of the outer function.
这是我们以前得到的同样的结果。
This is the same result that we had before.
好的，我们得到了数字名称，它将接受一个值
Okay, so we've got digit name which will receive a value
它是从我们立即调用的函数中获得的函数。
which is a function which is obtained from a function that we call immediately.
并且该内部函数将继续访问
And that inner function will continue to have access to the names variable of
外部函数。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以这就是结束。
the outer function. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So this is closure.
这是函数式编程中的大思想，关键思想。
This is the big idea, the key idea in functional programming.
这是好东西。
And this is the good stuff.
这是最好的部分。
This is the good part.
我们明天会花很多时间玩这个模型。
We're gonna spend a lot of time tomorrow playing with this model.
在我们继续下一个之前有什么问题吗，
Any questions before we go on to the next one,
是吗？&gt；&gt；演讲者4：那么，你解决了全局问题
yeah? &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: So, you solved the global
通过移动它到那里的可变问题，但是你说解决这个问题的方法是
variable problem by moving it in there but you said the solution to this was that
基本上，您移动调用，将所有内容移动到一个堆中？
basically you move the invocation, move everything into a heap?
太好了，那么现在堆中，你将有三个名称数组的实例吗？
Great, so now in heap are you going to have three instances of the names array?
如果您将警报数字名称称为三，然后是四，然后是五。
If you call alert digit name three then four then five.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No, so
这是个很好的问题。
that's a really good question.
所以您熟悉激活记录的概念
So you're familiar with the idea of an activation record
在编程语言中。
in a programming language.
所以激活记录将包含返回地址。
So the activation record will contain the return address.
包含所有输入参数，也可能包含本地参数
Contain all the input parameters and might also contain local
参数和她的局部变量之类的东西。
arguments and her local variables and stuff like that.
所以，在JavaScript中，或者在像这样的函数式语言中，
So, in JavaScript, or in a functional language like this,
激活时，函数对象将包含指向代码的指针。
the activation, a function object will contain a pointer to the code.
因此它知道调用函数时要执行什么，
So it knows what to execute when the function is invoked,
并且函数对象将包含对激活的引用
and the function object will contain a reference to the activation of
创建它的函数。
the function that created it.
所以这种情况下，这个函数或对象
So this case, this function or the object that is
由该函数表达式创建的将被链接
created by that function expression will be linked
到创建它的绿色函数的上下文中。
to the context of the green function that created it.
因此通过激活连接，它将可以访问名称
So through that activation connection it will have access to the names
变量不是创建它时使用的NAMES变量的值，而是
variable not to the value of the names variable that it was created with but
实际名称变量本身。
the actual names variable itself.
它总是可以访问它，并且
It will always have access to that and
只要它还活着就会继续拥有它。
will continue to have it as long as it survives.
如果在某个时候我说了数字名
If at some point I said digit name to
在这一点上未定义，所有这些东西都可以被垃圾收集。
undefined at that point all of that stuff can get garbage collected.
但在此之前，只要内部函数存活下来
But until then, as long as the inner function survives and
需要激活，它将保留它，垃圾收集器不会接触它。
needs that activation, it will keep it and the garbage collector will not touch it.
所以当我们调用数字名称时，
So when we call digit name,
我们将调用这个函数，它将简单地转到数组并返回值。
we'll be calling this function which will simply go to the array and return a value.
所以我们可以用一、二、三和
So we can call it with one, two, three, and
我们只是调用它并返回三个值。
we're just calling it and returning three values.
我们没有创造任何东西，因为我们只是称之为
We're not creating any stuff because we're just calling that
小功能。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：So
little function. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So
让我向您展示一个稍微复杂的示例。
let me show you a slightly more complex example.
这是淡出函数。
This is the fade function.
淡出功能是我们可以在浏览器中运行的功能，它
The fade function is something we might run in a browser which
将传入DOM元素的ID。
will pass in the ID of a DOM element.
并且它将该元素的颜色从
And it will change the colors of that element from
在几秒钟内逐渐从黄色变成白色
yellow to white gradually over a couple seconds and
这里是淡出函数。
so, here is that the fade function.
它将做的第一件事是，它将使用
First thing it will do is, it will use document that
按ID获取元素以查找ID并获取主导元素。
get element by ID to look up the ID and obtain a dominant element.
它将创建一个名为level的变量，并将其设置为1。
And it will create a variable called level and it will set it to 1.
它将创建一个名为step的函数，然后调用step timeout
It will create a function called step and it will then call step timeout which
将在100毫秒内调用Step，然后返回。
will call step in 100 milliseconds, and then it returns.
所以在这一点上，淡出函数已经完成了它的返回，它完成了。
So at this point, the fade function has finished its return, it's done.
突然，100毫秒后阶跃函数运行，所以
Suddenly, 100 milliseconds later the step function runs, so
STEP函数将转到其级别变量。
the step function will go to its level variable.
父函数的实际级别变量，
The actual level variable of the parent function,
并将其转换为十六进制字符。
and turn it into a hex character.
它将转到DOM元素中更改其背景色，
It will go to the DOM element in change its background color,
它将再次转到级别变量。
it will go to the level variable again.
如果小于十五，因为它是一个，我们会增加一个。
If it's less than fifteen which will be because it was one we will add one to it.
我们现在正在改变外部函数中变量的值。
We're now changing the value of the variable in the outer function.
我们将调用set timeout再次执行此操作
And we'll call set timeout to do this again and
我们将继续这样做，直到最终级别达到15，然后我们停止。
we'll keep doing it until eventually level gets up to 15 and then we stop.
在这一点上，垃圾收集器可以进入并将其全部取出。
And at that point, the garbage collector can come in and take it all out.
&gt；&gt；扬声器5：所以你最好打电话给你
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: So you better call you would
只是说，褪色75次，你不需要说，
just say, fade 75, times you don't have to say,
变量X等于淡出75，你只是淡出75。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：威尔
var X equals fade 75, you just fade 75. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Will
可能会给它起个名字。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：将是垃圾
be probably give it a name. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Will be garbage
收藏家如果我们连名字都不说？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不，
collector if we don't even name? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No,
我的意思是，淡出的争论可能是因为我们正在谈论
I mean I mean that the argument to fade will probably because we're talking to
一个DOM并且肯定被听到是字符串[INAUDIBLE]是的，但是的，所以
a DOM and certainly has been heard to be the strings [INAUDIBLE] yeah, but yeah, so
我们可以做到。
we can do that.
因此，假设有两个DOM元素，我们希望同时提供给它们。
So suppose there are two DOM elements and we want to feed them both simultaneously.
所以我们叫喂食马上褪色。
So we call feed a fade be immediately.
他们之间会有冲突吗？
Will there be any conflict between them?
答案是否定的，因为每次我们呼叫褪色，
And the answer is no because every time we call fade,
我们得到一个新的DOM变量，我们得到一个新的级别变量和一个新的阶跃函数。
we get a new DOM variable, we get a new level variable and a new step function.
它们不会相互干扰，它们都在自己的范围内
And they will not interfere with each other they're all within their own
函数作用域，并且将是完全唯一的。
function scopes and will be completely unique.
所以这个建筑的好处之一就是我们得到了
So one of the nice things about this construction is that we get that
分离。
separation.
所以我们可以在没有这些行为的情况下进行许多复杂的行为
So that we can have lots of complex behavior going on without those behaviors
互相干扰。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：每个
interfering with each other. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Each
调用淡出开始超时的时间会传递一个新实例
time you call fade start time out passes a new instance
DOM的阶跃函数，对吗？
of the step function to DOM, is that correct?
因此，DOM不鼓励收集这些步骤
And so, the DOM doesn't encourage collect those step
函数，直到调用它之后调用超时为止
functions until after its invoke the timeout after it's called
OUT函数。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：DOM是唯一的
out function. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The DOM is only
在与专栏相关的内容中，我们正在查看改变颜色的样式。
involved in that with column, we're looking at the style to change the color.
否则，DOM不会意识到任何-
Otherwise, the dom is not aware of that any-
&gt；&gt；扬声器5：对不起，setTimeout是-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: I'm sorry, setTimeout is-
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，setTimeout
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, the setTimeout
实际上并不属于JavaScript，
is, doesn't actually belong to JavaScript,
它确实属于浏览器。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：浏览器。
it does belong to the browser. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Browser.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：也有。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Also has it.
是的，所以每次我们调用Fade，我们将创建一个新的阶跃函数
Yeah, so each time we call fade, we will make a new step function and
我们将多次传递该步骤函数以设置超时
we'll pass that step function many times to set timeout
直到我们完成。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：我只是
until we finish. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: I was just
试图弄清楚为什么STEP不收集垃圾。
trying to get my head around why step doesn't get garbage collected.
那是因为浏览器。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对，因为
It's because the browser. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right, cuz the
浏览器正在将其保存在计时器队列中。&GT；&GT；扬声器5：好的，
browser's holding it in its timer queue. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Okay,
其计时器队列。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：和
its timer queue. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And
只要系统中的任何东西意识到根植于
and as long as anything in the system is aware of something that's rooted in
垃圾收集器不会碰它。&gt；&gt；扬声器5：好的，谢谢。
the garbage collector won't touch it. &gt;&gt; Speaker 5: Okay, thanks.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yes.
&gt；&gt；扬声器6：初始值是多少
&gt;&gt; Speaker 6: What's the initial value of
H你什么时候声明的？&GT；&GT；Douglas Crockford：第一次H
h when you declared that? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: First time H
将是字符串之一。&gt；&gt；扬声器6：和
will be the string one. &gt;&gt; Speaker 6: And
那么两根弦16做什么？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：16，
then what does the two string 16 do? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: 16,
toString 16表示生成十六进制字符，因此
toString 16 means make a hex character, so
这将使我们从1到F。
this will give us from one to F.
然后，我们将它们添加到这里
And then, we add them to here so
文件颜色将为纯白色，因此将为FFFFF
the file color will be pure white, so it'll be FFFFF